<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.code_industry.MasterPDFEditor</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.code_industry.MasterPDFEditor.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Master PDF Editor</name>
  <developer_name>Code Industry</developer_name>
  <summary>Master PDF Editor is a full solutions for work with PDF documents</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
  <url type="homepage">https://code-industry.net/masterpdfeditor/</url>
  <description>
    <ul>
      <li>Edit PDF text and images, Mark and annotate, Merge and split.</li>
      <li>JavaScript and Dynamic XFA form support.</li>
      <li>Validation Forms and Calculate Values.</li>
      <li>Adding a digital signature and Signing PDF Documents.</li>
      <li>Fast and simple PDF forms fill out.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source">https://code-industry.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/masterpdfeditor-5.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <kudos>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
  </kudos>
  <releases>
     <release version="5.9.94" date="2025-09-15">
         <description></description>
     </release>
     <release version="5.9.94" date="2025-09-11">
      <description>
         <ul>
          <li>Added the functionality to compare documents.</li>
          <li>Added the functionality to edit watermarks and backgrounds in the document.</li>
          <li>Added the ability to insert default initials into documents.</li>
          <li>Fixed bugs related to converting files to PDF/A-2. Now all files are converted to PDF/A-2 properly.</li>
          <li>Added support for printing from the context menu on Windows.</li>
          <li>Improved preview area in the Page Layout window.</li>
          <li>Added automatic scrolling to the selected objects in the Object TreeView tab.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug with opening Certificate Manager on macOS starting from version 15.</li>
          <li>Improvements to the watermark placed in the demo version.</li>
          <li>A range of fixes made to the Print functionality.</li>
          <li>Fixed a number of bugs in the user interface.</li>
          <li>Fixed multiple issues related to operations of the View menu.</li>
          <li>Bug fix for creating files in the wrong file format when using a virtual PDF printer.</li>
          <li>Fixed incorrect comment and form importing in FDF format.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues with displaying comments.</li>
          <li>Resolved issues related to creating, displaying, and modifying page sizes.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug with restoring the last view settings on macOS.</li>
          <li>Resolved an issue with editing text objects using the Edit Text tool.</li>
         </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.9.89" date="2025-04-07">
      <description>
         <ul>
          <li>Added automatic text recognition functionality.</li>
          <li>Added document printing in a Booklet mode.</li>
          <li>Implemented support for scaling PDF documents using the touchpad on Apple laptops.</li>
          <li>Implemented the ability to rotate objects using a rotation handle located above objects.</li>
          <li>Added a page selection feature that allows selecting pages with check boxes in the Navigation panel.</li>
          <li>Added the ability to specify coordinates using mathematical operators in the object inspector.</li>
          <li>Implemented numerous improvements and fixes to the printing process.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with printing documents in Landscape and Portrait orientations.</li>
          <li>Fixed incorrect display of the application icon on Wayland.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues occurring during the export of PDF documents to text format.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue in the object inspector’s functionality.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug causing repeated initial styles on macOS.</li>
          <li>Resolved an issue where a file would be overwritten despite selecting “No” in the “Replace File” dialog.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug related to creating a new session when canceling session creation.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with text recognition on a specific page.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue related to moving a file tab after its update.</li>
          <li>Resolved a bug affecting the border color change of the typewriter during editing.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue that caused the reset of bookmark styles and colors defined in their properties.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that invalidated signatures upon saving a document.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue causing page size changes after converting a document to PDF/A format.</li>
          <li>Resolved an issue when extracting pages to a network folder.</li>
          <li>Fixed a crash caused by using hotkeys for printing with saved settings.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.9.87" date="2024-02-24">
      <description>
          <ul>
          <li>Improved converting a file format from PDF to PDF/A.</li>
          <li>Improved creating and editing bookmarks.</li>
          <li>Added the functionality to save custom page size.</li>
          <li>Added the functionality to split files by specified page ranges.</li>
          <li>Improved the document display when switching between pages.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues when creating, opening, and editing documents.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with the page display on the navigation panel.</li>
          <li>Improved the display of some interface elements.</li>
          <li>Improved export to the TXT and XLSX file formats.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues with adding headers and footers.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues with scanning.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with the increase in document size.</li>
          <li>Fixed bugs with duplex and color printing.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with a signature when deleting a page.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug with activating a program.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.9.86" date="2024-10-29">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added new functionalities for managing layers.</li>
          <li>Added the ability to select the latest settings when printing a new document.</li>
          <li>Enhanced compatibility with PDF 1.3 format specification.</li>
          <li>Improved settings for the page display and layout.</li>
          <li>Improved navigation in a document and between documents.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with saving a file on macOS.</li>
          <li>Improved the display of some interface elements.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with editing headers and footers.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug with the display of some PDF-files.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues with printing and highlighting form fields.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with adding initials.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.9.82" date="2024-02-02"/>
    <release version="5.9.81" date="2023-12-08">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added the ability to insert image files using drag and drop.</li>
          <li>Fixed critical issue when minimizing main window of the application.</li>
          <li>Multiple minor fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.9.80" date="2023-12-05"/>
    <release version="5.9.70" date="2023-10-10"/>
    <release version="5.9.61" date="2023-08-29"/>
    <release version="5.9.60" date="2023-08-22"/>
    <release version="5.9.50" date="2023-06-28"/>
    <release version="5.9.40" date="2023-03-11"/>
    <release version="5.9.35" date="2023-01-26"/>
    <release version="5.9.30" date="2023-01-20"/>
    <release version="5.9.21" date="2023-01-19"/>
    <release version="5.9.10" date="2022-11-09"/>
    <release version="5.9.06" date="2022-10-26"/>
    <release version="5.8.70" date="2022-07-04"/>
    <release version="5.8.65" date="2022-06-24"/>
    <release version="5.8.63" date="2022-06-16"/>
    <release version="5.8.52" date="2022-05-02"/>
    <release version="5.8.49" date="2022-04-12"/>
    <release version="5.8.46" date="2022-04-03"/>
    <release version="5.8.33" date="2022-01-21"/>
    <release version="5.8.32" date="2022-01-19"/>
    <release version="5.8.30" date="2022-01-03"/>
    <release version="5.8.20" date="2021-11-11"/>
    <release version="5.8.18" date="2021-11-10"/>
    <release version="5.8.15" date="2021-11-08"/>
    <release version="5.8.06" date="2021-09-29"/>
    <release version="5.8.03" date="2021-09-26"/>
    <release version="5.7.90" date="2021-08-01"/>
    <release version="5.7.60" date="2021-05-06"/>
    <release version="5.7.53" date="2021-04-06"/>
    <release version="5.7.40" date="2021-03-17"/>
    <release version="5.7.31" date="2021-03-11"/>
    <release version="5.7.20" date="2021-01-31"/>
    <release version="5.7.10" date="2021-01-24"/>
    <release version="5.7.08" date="2021-01-19"/>
    <release version="5.7.00" date="2021-01-16"/>
    <release version="5.6.80" date="2020-11-24"/>
    <release version="5.6.49" date="2020-09-15"/>
    <release version="5.6.42" date="2020-08-19"/>
    <release version="5.6.40" date="2020-08-18"/>
    <release version="5.6.29" date="2020-07-29"/>
    <release version="5.6.20" date="2020-07-10"/>
    <release version="5.6.09" date="2020-07-05">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Recent files to the main page and main menu</li>
          <li>Added Poster and Multipage printing modes</li>
          <li>Added customizable Toolbar settings</li>
          <li>The program is fully optimized for the latest Linux distributions</li>
          <li>Fixed issue with incorrect Initial View</li>
          <li>Fixed issue with documents being opened on the wrong page</li>
          <li>Fixed issue with ClosePage event</li>
          <li>Added SubmitForm event message</li>
          <li>Improved file saving speed</li>
          <li>Fixed area calculation issues</li>
          <li>Fixed issues with File Open dialog (focus loss in Linux)</li>
          <li>Fixed file saving issue</li>
          <li>Fixed issues with incorrect display of some PDF documents</li>
          <li>Fixed bug which initiated infinite recursion when processing color in some documents</li>
          <li>Fixed issue with watermarks creating from files</li>
          <li>Fixed issue which crashed the application when printing</li>
          <li>Improved JavaScript support</li>
          <li>Fixed OpenSSL issues in some operating systems</li>
          <li>Fixed numerous issues with printing</li>
          <li>Other minor bugs fixed</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.4.38" date="2019-07-09">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Noticeably improved drag-and-drop for all supported OS and fixed all known issues with it</li>
          <li>Fixed several different issues</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <update_contact>rymg19_at_gmail.com</update_contact>
</component>
